Lisbon...
It's over. It's done.
I just want you to know
I'm okay.
And I'm gonna miss you.
And that's what police do.
We help people that are in trouble
and we stop people
from making trouble.
It's a hard job sometimes
but I think it's
the best job there is.
What about you?
Does anybody want to be
a police officer when they grow up?
Well, there's time to think about it.
Any questions?
Oh, oh, oh! Oh!
Oh, oh!
Did you ever shoot somebody?
Well, actually, yes.
Did they die?
Point is, there are
bad people in the world.
Not all, but some.
"And sometimes you have
to do things you don't wanna do"
"to make sure worse things
don't happen."
- "Was there lots of blood?"
- "I'm afraid that's all the time we have."
- "What do we say?"
- "Thank you, chief Lisbon!"
Hey, Henry, what's up?
There's a man here
wants to speak with you.
An Agent Abbott
uh, with the FBI.
- Abbott?
- That's what he said.
- Send him in.
- Okay.
Yes?
"Do you want me
to send him in now?"
Yes.
Hi, Lisbon.
Hmm.
Well, you... have a nice place.
Hmm?
You've been here, what, 18 months?
- Have you heard from Jane?
- Nope.
Nothing? No email
no phone call?
No.
Hmm.
What about Rigsby
or Van Pelt?
Have they heard anything?
I'm having dinner with them soon.
Why don't you join us?
You could ask them yourself.
Mm-hmm. And Cho?
Haven't heard from him in ages.
I don't know where Jane is
and Frankly, I don't care.
No? Well...
You two were so close.
It was a long time ago.
When are you guys gonna
give up chasing him?
Oh, we're the FBI.
We don't give up.
That is a nice shell.
It's a cowrie.
Oh.
- May I?
- Sure.
You know, they say a shell
always carries around
the sound of the ocean with it.
Ah.
"Dear Lisbon"
"I hope this finds you well."
"All's well here."
"I have my routines."
"Weather's finally turned."
"It's a little cooler."
"Far from cold."
"The ocean's still warm."
"And with the warm ocean currents
comes an abundance of sea life."
"Just yesterday, I watched a pot
of dolphins play so close to shore"
"I could almost touch them."
"They're the kind of things
I think you'd enjoy."
Unbelievable.
Cheaper than yesterday, but more
expensive than last week.
Patrick! Patrick!
Oh, really, guys?
Very persistent, I must say.
Very persistent.
Huh? What have we got here?
Yeah.
"Where is it?"
Hey!
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
"Good morning", Victor.
"Ah, Mr. Jane. Good morning."
No, no, no, no,
no, no.
"Cha... Charre...
charreteras?"
What... uh...
"Charreteras. Charreteras.
Charreteras."
"Yes."
- "What are they called?"
- Ah, epaulettes.
Epaulettes. "Charreteras."
"Yes. Yes."
Ah!
Hey, Hugo.
How you doing, boy?
Good? Good, Hugo?
Good boy.
Alfredo...
Hi.
Hello.
From the US?
You weren't fooled
by my impeccable Spanish?
No. Anyway...
You're reading. Sorry.
Thing is, uh...
I miss speaking English.
Roger's the only other
English speaker
and he's... well, he's not
a great talker.
Turns out being understood
is an underrated pleasure.
- I can imagine.
- Mm.
I'll leave you alone.
No problem.
Looks like you're nearly finished.
Do you want it when I'm finished?
I wouldn't mind it.
It's not easy to get books
in English around here.
Okay.
- Is it any good?
- You like murder mysteries?
Not really.
- Then you probably won't like it.
- Well, I'll take it anyway.
Beggars can't be choosers
can they?
No, they can't.
Do you wanna join me?
Sure.
Patrick.
- Kim.
- Hi.
So you're from the, uh, southeast?
Virginia?
Good ear.
You?
Well, I... I lived all over.
Right now I live here.
I was on the other side of the Island
but people told me the beaches
on this side were better.
- That's true.
- You here with your wife?
No, just me.
Oh, yeah, no. My wife, uh...
Uh... not married anymore.
- You?
- Me? No.
Great. I mean, it's great if you...
If you like not being married...
being single.
- I do.
- Great.
- "Thank you very much."
- "Yes, welcome."
I came here to get away
to think about things.
What are you thinking about?
I've been offered a promotion at work
but I'm not sure I want it.
- Why is that?
- Oh... It's more work.
It's more hassle.
Eh, more money, but is it worth it?
Well, sounds like you're asking yourself
the right questions.
Must be strange to live here.
It's so beautiful. I...
I think if I were here full-time
I'd feel like I was living in some kind
of dream world, you know?
Ah, sometimes it's like that.
There's nothing wrong
with dream worlds, right?
- You're here to stay.
- Maybe.
Man of mystery.
Really?
I don't mean to be mysterious.
My wife died.
Some things happened.
I did some things, and...
I don't really know
how to talk about it yet.
I guess that's why
I still wear the ring.
I'm just... Not ready.
I think I understand.
Anyway, that's why I'm here.
It's not a bad place to be.
- Right? It's beautiful.
- It's paradise.
Exactly.
Morning.
Hi.
Do you speak English?
Yes, sir. I speak
very good, sir.
Ah. Good.
What's your name?
Morales.
Franklin Morales, sir.
- Morales, huh?
- Mm.
Have you seen this guy?
No, sir.
Okay then.
- If you see him...
- Mm-hmm.
- You'll tell me, yes?
- Yes, sir.
- All right.
- Mm-hmm.
- "Thank you very much."
All right, fellas, let's get settled
then we'll go get
something to eat.
Hey, Roger, what's up?
"Thank you."
Roger, Kim.
Kim, Roger.
- Hi.
- My eyes were... Fluid cobras.
Yeah. Good to see you.
How long has he been here?
Uh, not sure. Long time.
You can tell.
"One moment."
Jane.
Oh. Uh, excuse me.
Hello?
- It's Franklin.
- Hey, Franklin. What's up?
Three big American police
checked in.
Looking for you.
- Hmm. They're there now?
- Yes.
Okay, well, see what else
you can find out.
- I'll be in touch, okay?
- Yes, of course.
Bye.
Is everything all right?
Uh, yeah. Fine.
Uh, just some...
Some people who wanna
meet with me.
Listen, I have to head
back up to town.
- Do you wanna come with me?
- Sure.
See you around.
- I'm sure I will.
- Bye.
- That's a nice shirt.
- Thanks.
Well, this was nice.
I know you have people to see.
Yes, uh, unfortunately
I do, yeah.
No problem.
Um, but I was wondering...
Do you, uh, know a good
place around here for dinner?
- Are you asking me out for dinner?
- Yeah.
I figure you'll know a good
place where the locals go.
Yeah, uh, I do. Um...
Yes, I do...
Well, why don't we meet here
at, uh...
Oh, I don't know... eight?
- Deal.
- Okay.
- Eight o'clock.
- See ya then.
The man who asks about you
is Abbott.
That is the name
on the register.
Hmm. Where is he now?
Eating. The other two men
are with him, but they leave.
- Ah. Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
Who's that guy?
Danny Otero.
Sells drugs.
Comes here to buy heroin
from Vietnamese.
Bad business.
How you say? Um...
Lousy Tipper.
Yeah. Yeah.
Abbott.
How the heck are you?
And here we thought
we were gonna have to turn over
every rock on this Island
to find you.
I heard you were here.
Well, it's only polite
to stop by and say hi.
Hmm.
Oh, how was the flight?
Bumpy.
Pretty confident of you
to front up like this.
The extradition laws are on my side.
I know you can't touch me.
Who said I wanted
to touch you?
- I'm here to make you an offer.
- Oh.
The powers-that-be
decided that you
could be valuable to the FBI.
The Bureau is willing to drop
all the charges against you
if you come and work for us.
For the FBI?
That's right.
There are the terms.
You know, I wanna be very clear.
I don't like this deal.
If it were up to me
you would be headed home
in a cargo plane
with a sack over your head.
But, hey, I'm just the messenger.
Interesting proposition.
I'm not buying it.
No?
Whatever my feelings are
about it...
This is a good deal, Jane.
You really need to consider it.
I am done with that life.
I did what I had to do
and I've moved on.
That life was a job
that you were very good at.
If you come back, you can
help a lot of people.
You have a gift.
It's not a gift.
Whatever it is, it'll
get you off this Island
and you can start
your life again.
I have. Thank you.
Okay.
We'll be here for another day
if you change your mind.
How'd you find me?
The letters to your girlfriend Lisbon.
You know, it was pretty smart
to send them to your carny friends
and have them sneak them
over to her.
Just not quite smart enough.
So I finally managed
to hack through the firewall
and it turns out
the cyber mastermind stealing credit card
numbers is an 11-year-old from Minneapolis.
What?
Yeah. He was
selling them to his friends
so they could buy
limited-edition sneakers.
- Did he get arrested?
- I don't know.
We turned the information
over to the Minneapolis PD.
Actually, they did.
I checked.
- And he's gonna be tried as a juvenile.
- Oh, well, there you go.
So the digital surveillance
company is going well, huh?
Yeah. We've been up and running now
for, uh, 15 months, and...
already turning a tidy profit
believe it or not.
- Yeah.
- Nice.
How are things here?
Same. You know, it's mostly
DUIs, stolen bikes...
But I like it that way.
It's nice and quiet.
It's the babysitter.
Excuse me.
Hello?
Maddy's got a slight fever.
Grace worries. I try
and tell her it's nothing.
- But first baby, you know?
- Sure.
- Can I ask you something, Wayne?
- Mm.
- Do you ever miss the CBI?
- Hmm.
Sure. Sometimes.
I mean, Grace and I are so busy.
I don't really have much time
to think about it.
- Things are so hectic.
- Hmm.
I used to miss it, but not anymore.
Yeah. Everything here's good.
You know, it's just...
it's good.
- That's great, boss.
- I am not your boss anymore.
She says her fever's up to 102.7.
Oh. I'm sorry.
We're out of here.
- I'm so sorry.
- No, it's fine.
But I'll walk you to your car.
So... those people
that wanted to meet with you.
- Did you meet with them?
- Yeah.
How'd it go?
Uh, it was interesting.
They made me a job offer.
Hmm?
Basically, if I go and work for them
then I can go back to the US.
Sounds good.
Not really.
I've kind of moved on.
It would be going backwards.
And I don't think that's healthy.
What is it that you... do, anyway?
- What do I do?
- Yeah.
I, uh... I look for people.
- Sounds intriguing.
- It is. Was.
It was fun.
Still, you get to go home.
Aren't there things that you miss?
Sure, of course.
Thank you for this.
I needed the company.
I didn't think I did, but, uh...
Ah, it turns out that... I do.
Who doesn't?
You wanna go dancing?
Yeah.
It's a beautiful night.
It is.
I think there's somebody
following us.
- I'll just go and talk to them.
- No! Patrick!
- Come on.
- No, it's okay. It's fine.
I speak the lingo.
- What are you...
- Hey, guys, come out where I can see you.
Let's have a...
Whoa...
Oh, my God.
Patrick?
Ah...
That feels good.
You smell nice.
- You should see a doctor.
- No... No.
You could have a concussion.
Nah, I just...
Just need to rest.
I was very, uh, drunk last night.
Yes.
What happened?
You got beat up.
Here.
Thank you.
Oh, that is so good.
How are you feeling?
Better now, after this.
- You make good tea.
- Thank you.
I got a text this morning.
My work.
I have to go back today.
I have a midday flight
and I have to pack, and...
Yeah, I understand.
You gotta go back.
- Yeah. Sorry.
- Oh, no, it's... it's fine.
Thanks for everything.
Oh...
I really had a wonderful time
with you, Patrick.
Mm.
Anyway...
Hugo!
Alfredo?
What happened?
Pow.
Hey.
Hi.
I was hoping
I'd find you here.
I wanted to give you something.
Oh, thank you.
No, thank you...
for dinner and everything.
I...
You're right.
Being understood
is an underrated pleasure.
Let me give you my home
phone number
in case you ever make it
back to the States.
You never know.
You might wanna give me a call.
I might.
Goodbye, Patrick.
Good luck with your decision.
You know, one thing...
Going back doesn't have
to mean going backwards.
It can mean moving on.
- Abbott.
- Hey, G-man.
- I'm ready to come home.
- Wow. That is good news.
But on my terms.
Is that clear?
And when we get back
to the US
I want a meeting with
whatever powers-that-be
to make clear that those
are the terms.
I'm sure we can work out
something like that.
- And I want Lisbon there.
- "Why?"
Lisbon's there, or I don't do it.
And if you say she's gonna
be there, and she's not
I will make it clear to your bosses
that I will work
with any FBI agent except you.
You'll have done all the work to get me
and get nothing for it.
Do we have an understanding?
What time do you want us
to pick you up?
I'll let you know.
I got something I gotta do first.
- "Franklin?"
- Patrick? How are you?
Good. I'm very good.
Uh, I need your help.
You said that Danny Otero
was buying some heroin
from some Vietnamese dealers.
You should have nothing to do
with Danny Otero.
Me? No, of course not.
I'm not going anywhere near him.
Do you know if he's already
made the buy?
No. No, Vietnamese guests
only check in this morning.
Excellent. I need you
to find out three things for me.
I can find out anything.
First, when will the deal happen?
Second, what room
will they be in?
What else?
Uh, yes.
Uh, when the Vietnamese
will be eating.
No problem. They never eat.
Always in the bar.
Excellent, Franklin.
You're very good.
Very, very good.
Thank you.
"Thank you."
Good afternoon.
Sorry for the interruption.
Uh, I assume one of you
speaks English.
I do.
Patrick Jane.
Pleased to meet you.
What's this about?
I know you're drug dealers.
I don't judge.
I'm wanted for homicide
myself in the US.
what I wanna discuss
is a mutual acquaintance...
Danny Otero.
What about him?
Well, I thought I should
warn you. He's flipped.
He's working as an informer
to the police.
He's teamed up with an FBI
agent named Abbott.
How do you know this?
Well, I'm working with Abbott myself
on a different deal.
That's how Otero's name came up.
If you have any business
with Danny Otero
word to the wise...
You might wanna be careful.
See ya.
Abbott.
I'll be in room 1443
in 15 minutes.
Here in the hotel?
I'm having a little goodbye drink
with some friends.
Just identify yourself at the door
And they'll come get me.
Yes?
Abbott. FBI.
Excuse me?
Abbott, FBI.
Didn't Patrick Jane
tell you I was coming?
One moment.
- Did you sell us to the police?
- What?
Did you sell us to the police?
No, no, no...
The feds are right outside.
The FBI.
"You think you can get away
with this?"
The hell with this.
All right...
- I'm telling you, I'm not...
- FBI! Don't move!
Don't move!
Put your hands on your head.
Put the gun down.
"Leave that... Now."
Good job. All right. Now everybody get down
on the ground.
Down on the ground.
"To the ground."
"On your stomach."
Huh?
Ah, that's nice.
Very nice.
The only question is...
Where's Patrick Jane?
Abbott, what happened?
You set this up.
You're the one
who knocked on the door.
My terms.
I need you to read them
and sign it.
- We can work with this.
- Excellent. Sign it, please.
All right.
Five more copies.
Sign those, too, please.
They're for you.
I keep the original.
- All right. Let's go.
- Ah, one second.
Now we can go.
Mr. Jane!
Jane.
Cho.
Ha!
You never cease to amaze me.
I got him from here, guys.
So you joined the FBI, huh?
Yeah.
Finished training
at Quantico five months ago.
Wow. Look at you.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
Yeah.
- It's this way.
- Okay.
Where are your socks?
Uh... I don't know.
Did they put a chip
in your neck?
Not that I know of.
Why do you ask?
Ah, you just don't seem
too happy to see me.
I am happy to see you.
I just wish it was under
different circumstances.
Why is that?
I don't think you and the FBI
are gonna get along very well.
I don't think they really
understand how you operate.
Ah. They'll loosen up
once they get to know me.
Mm-hmm.
Second door on the left.
Hey.
Hello.
Nice beard.
Thank you.
Thank you for the letters.
Oh, I missed you.
I missed you, too.
What's going on, huh?
Why am I here?
- You'll see. It's gonna be great.
- What?
Trust me.
All right, let's get this started.
Jane... these are the charges
pending against you...
Homicide, obstruction of justice
aggravated assault
grand theft auto, etcetera.
You're looking at 20 to life.
But all of that can go away
if you agree to serve as a consultant
for the FBI for at least five years.
You will be under my supervision
on federal parole
which may be revoked
at any time at my discretion.
You screw up, run away
do anything that I don't like
and you'll be in the jailhouse.
Sign, and we have a deal.
Interesting.
As you're aware
you have already agreed
to some terms.
I didn't agree to those.
I signed indicating that I read them.
- Same difference.
- No, it's not, believe me.
Firstly, no parole.
I'm a free man.
And secondly
Lisbon has to work with me.
- Hey, hello?
- Well, you won't need Lisbon.
I've already assembled a team
to work with you.
- Oh, that's not negotiable.
- I have a job, okay?
I'm not gonna drop everything
just because you suddenly
decided to come back.
W... we'll talk.
There are some other stipulations.
Easy stuff.
I'm sure we can figure them out.
But none of this applies.
This...
I don't think you're hearing me, Jane.
You are on US soil now.
I am the federal government
and I am telling you that that is a napkin.
This... is the deal.
Take it...
or leave it.
- I'll leave it.
- Oh, that's too bad.
You made a mistake,
but, hey...
Kim?
Agent Fischer.
Mr. Jane will be going
to a detention suite.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I'll make the arrangements.
Oh, yeah, I'm not fussy.
If you have one with a view
I'll take it.
If not, uh, whatever
as long as I can make some tea.
Who is she, and what is a detention suite?
Don't worry, Lisbon.
It's all under control.